# Ishan Jaidka

(425) 770-0077 | ishan@jaidka.dev

Github: Ishan-Jaidka
LinkedIn: ishanjaidka
Portfolio: ishan.jaidka.dev

Software engineer with 1 year of professional full stack development experience and a passion for learning, interpersonal connections, and all things web development, automation, and robotics. Looking for an opportunity to combine my curiosity about new technology with my software engineering background to help build the future.

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

# Jumpshot — Remote

Nov 2022 - Present

## **Software Engineer**

- Built an end to end UI/UX prototype for an entertainment venue to present to investors and secure funding including the following:
  - User registration, game selection, and game logic using React.
  - Backend using MongoDB, Express.js, and Node.js.
  - Virtual reality of gameplay using A-Frame.
  - Service to connect and orchestrate the hardware component, motion tracking AI, and frontend using Socket.io.

# GetSetUp — Remote

Mar 2022 - Nov 2022

## **Software Engineer**

- Optimized website search experience by adjusting Algolia configurations and implementing event based UX tracking to quantify the effects of each change viewable in Metabase reports.
- Reduced a company estimated \$1m/year in support costs by enabling agents to quickly and effectively interact with multiple users and decreasing common support tickets through the following:
  - Migrated to Zendesk CRM by building a custom help center, integrating the chat widget, connecting user databases via event based microservices, and building an import service for existing data.
  - Worked with existing company infrastructure to pipe contextual data to Zendesk tickets for class chat sessions and identify users to agents.

# Edge & Spoke — Redmond, WA

Sept 2016 - Oct 2020

Assistant Sales Manager, Bike Fit Manager, Bike and Ski Technician

Managed a team of associates and inventory to ensure customer satisfaction and loyalty through effective communication for a diverse customer base.

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Capstone** — *Automated Greenhouse*

Sept 2021 - Jun 2022

Modular greenhouse automation and data collection using microcontrollers, AWS backend, and Android app UI communicating via a REST API.

Awarded Bellevue College's Best C.S. Capstone Project 21/22.

API: Designed and built an AWS hosted REST API to create client-server architecture and implement CRUD operations and IoT communication, allowing easy, controlled frontend access to all cloud services.

**Microcontroller**: Connected ESP32 to AWS IoT Core, used MQTT to upload sensor data to Timestream & control devices, 3D printed custom enclosures.

AWS Backend: Designed and built databases on AWS RDS & Timestream.

**Android app:** Built a user-friendly frontend with Kotlin & Android Studio.

#### **Skills**

Highly motivated self-starter with excellent communication, problem solving, and interpersonal skills. Lifetime learner, tinkerer, and team collaborator experienced in both Agile and Waterfall methodologies.

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Typescript, Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS, SQL, Java, C++, C#

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

React, Next.js, Node.js, Jira, Github, Postman, MySQL, Algolia, Zendesk, Visual Studio Code, AWS, Arduino IDE, IoT, Kotlin, GraphQL

## **CLOUD EXPERIENCE**

AWS: Lambda, S3, RDS, API Gateway, IoT Core, Timestream, CloudWatch, SQS, SNS, DynamoDB, Rekognition, IAM, EC2, CloudFormation

**Heroku:** Node.js with Github Continuous Integration

# **EDUCATION**

B.S. Computer Science, cum laude Bellevue College Jan 2019 - Jun 2022

Bioengineering Core Classes
University of Pittsburgh
Sept 2012 - Dec 2015
Interned with Dr. Nettleship testing
ceramic materials for culturing
human liver cells in-vitro

#### **INTERESTS**

Restoring & rebuilding cars & motorcycles, 3D modeling & printing, PC building, skiing, hiking with my dog, bicycling